Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Today we are going to continue our discussion on file systems.
今天我们将继续讨论文件系统。
If you remember, last time we are discussing about,
如果你还记得，上次我们讨论的是关于...
we ended our lecture with the discussion of the first file systems.
我们在讲座结束时讨论了第一个文件系统。
And we chose the version of the next version of the file
我们选择了文件的下一个版本的版本。
system in unique bsd after original version.
原始版本之后的Unique BSD系统。
And this has a lot of quite a few innovations.
这个有很多相当多的创新。
And we went over a few last time,
上次我们讲了一些内容，
mostly the innovation or about improving the performance,
主要是关于创新或提高性能的事情。
like different block sizes,
比如不同的块大小，
basically improving the rotational latency.
基本上是改善旋转延迟。
A few more features are going to improve the performance.
还有一些功能将会提高性能。
The one thing we didn't go over is the organization of the directories.
我们没有讨论的一件事是目录的组织。
So what is the problem here?
那么问题是什么？
So assume that you have a very large directory with many entries.
假设你有一个非常大的目录，其中包含许多条目。
Now, if you remember the early file systems,
现在，如果你还记得早期的文件系统，
organized directories as lists, this was,
将目录组织为列表形式，这是一种方法，
in the case of a fact,
在事实情况下，
the microsoft dose of first file system or arrays
微软的首个文件系统或数组的剂量
of entries or an entry is a file name and the I node
条目或一个条目是一个文件名和I节点。
corresponding to that file name.
对应于该文件名。
I know, if you remember,
我知道，如果你记得的话，
it contains the entire information about where which are the blocks
它包含了关于每个块的位置信息的全部内容。
of that particular file,
那个特定文件的
as well as other information about that file,
以及有关该文件的其他信息，
like access rights and things like that.
像访问权限和诸如此类的东西。
The time was on last updated and other information.
时间是上次更新的和其他信息。
The challenge with that is that say,
这个挑战在于，假设...
I want to locate 15, right?
我想要定位到15，对吗？
And whenever you are going to and is a command line,
每当你要进入命令行时，
or you are going to write a file names to say,
或者你要写一个文件来命名它们。
caesar contact to open,
请联系凯撒进行开通。
you need to find that file name because in the directory,
你需要找到那个文件的名称，因为它在目录中。
because the entry in the directory of that file name,
是因为该文件名在目录中的条目，
because that entry will give you the I node.
因为该条目将提供给您I节点。
And the I node will tell you where are the data blocks on the disk of that file.
I节点会告诉你文件在磁盘上的数据块位置。
But if the directory is organized like a list or an array of entries,
但是如果目录的组织方式类似于条目的列表或数组，
then the only way to locate that file is linear search.
那么唯一的方法就是进行线性搜索来定位该文件。
If the director is very large,
如果主管非常庞大，
it is linear search, it's expensive.
这是线性搜索，它很耗费资源。
Even more,
更重要的是，
you may need your meaning.
你可能需要你的意思。
You may need to read the entire directory just to find a file.
你可能需要读取整个目录才能找到一个文件。
Again,
请再说一遍。
if the directory is large,
如果目录很大，
you may have to load all the blocks which are storing this large directory.
你可能需要加载存储这个大目录的所有块。
Again, just to find the fire.
再次强调，只是为了找到问题的根源。
What is a solution?
解决方案是指解决问题或满足需求的方法或策略。它是针对特定问题或挑战的一种计划或行动方案，旨在达到预期的目标或结果。解决方案可以包括技术、流程、策略、工具或组合等多种元素。
The solution is to find a better structure than a list of one and an array.
解决方案是找到比一个列表和一个数组更好的数据结构。
If you want to search water of some better structure to search
如果你想寻找一些更好结构的水进行搜索
than at least an ordinary,
至少比普通的好一点，
you learn about many of those.
你会学到很多关于这些的知识。
Can you give an example?
你能给一个例子吗？
What would you do?
你会做什么？
If you had to design a directory data structure,
如果你需要设计一个目录数据结构，
which is much more efficient in terms of search?
在搜索方面，哪个更高效？
It's a binary tree, right?
这是一棵二叉树，对吗？
Yeah, that's pretty good.
是的，那很不错。
And it's even better.
而且它甚至更好。
Here.
在这里。
We can have ab tree.
我们可以使用AB树。
And when you have a tree, a surgery,
当你有一棵树，一场手术，
the depth of the tree is what gives you the complexity of locating
树的深度决定了定位的复杂度。
that the particular,
那个特定的，
in our case, file,
在我们的情况下，文件，
which is a leaf in that tree.
在那棵树中，哪一个是叶子节点。
This is for you, just aab tree.
这是给你的，只是一个aab树。
It's a more sophisticated search tree.
这是一棵更复杂的搜索树。
If you remember,
如果你还记得的话，
this is just aa reminder for to refresh your memory.
这只是一个提醒，帮助你恢复记忆。
Here, a node is pointing out at a lower level,
这里，一个节点指向一个较低级别。
a on to an array.
将a添加到一个数组中。
And that array contains values,
而且该数组包含值，
which are smaller than the value of the paranoid.
小于偏执值的值。
In this case, 100 points to this array of values.
在这种情况下，将100个点分配给这个值数组。
And all these values, 48, 50,
所有这些值，48，50，
79 are less than 100.
79小于100。
Also, the following.
另外，还有以下内容。
Now, the sibling node of 100, 1,
现在，100和1的兄弟节点是：
55 now is going to point to a set of values,
55现在将指向一组值，
to an array of values,
转换为值的数组
which are lower than itself,
比它自己小的数值，
but higher than its sibling on the left right and on.
但是比它左右两侧的兄弟节点都要高。
So these are numbers between 120, 8and 140,
这些是介于120、8和140之间的数字。
and so forth.
等等，诸如此类。
Eventually, you need to get the leaves,
最终，你需要获取叶子节点。
and let's see how to find a value of the lead at the leaf.
让我们看看如何找到叶子节点的值。
So let's see how this is used in the context of directories,
那么让我们看看在目录的上下文中如何使用它。
in the context of directories.
在目录的上下文中。
How do we get?
我们如何获得？
A the number is easy to get?
这个数字容易得到吗？
You just hash is the name of the file.
你只需要对文件名进行哈希处理。
Now we get a number.
现在我们得到了一个数字。
And hopefully the hash is good enough.
希望哈希函数足够好。
The probability of collisions is very small.
碰撞的概率非常小。
But this is what it is.
但事实就是如此。
It's exactly, it's a binary search tree.
没错，它是一棵二叉搜索树。
Sorry, it's a big tree.
抱歉，这是一棵大树。
It is a values in the beatrice,
这是在beatrice中的一个值。
are the hash is of the file makes.
文件的哈希值是否正确。
And you can see here on the leaves,
你可以在叶子上看到，
you are going to see to have the entries in the directory,
你需要查看目录中的条目。
which again, is the name of the file, a name,
再次强调，这是文件的名称，一个名字。
and the file number.
以及文件编号。
Or I note any questions?
还是我记下任何问题？
I
我
so in this particular case,
所以在这种特殊情况下，
you see that the hash two out two,
你看到了哈希值为2的两个输出。
it's c 194.
这是 c 194。
And you are looking through the beatles.
你正在浏览披头士乐队。
First of all, you are going to look at the values,
首先，你需要查看这些值。
which are you are looking to the values to the consecutive values says
你是在寻找连续值中的哪些值？
that the value on the left is lower,
左边的值较低，
the value on the right,
右边的值
it's higher,
它更高。
then c one, 94.
然后是 C 一号，94分。
And then you are going to pick the node corresponding to that,
然后你将选择与之对应的节点。
which is for the range.
这是用于范围的。
Then you are going to go on level down.
那么你将会降一个层级。
For instance, in this case,
例如，在这种情况下，
c 194 is smaller than the first value.
c 194 小于第一个值。
At the first level,
在第一层级上，
you are going to go take and go to the arrays pointed out by that value.
你将要去获取并访问由该值指向的数组。
Note eighty one one zero two o k because remember,
注意八一一零二，好的，因为记住，
eighty one zero one one zero two,
八一零一一零二,
which is a last left mosque.
最后一个剩下的清真寺是哪一个？
Now here,
现在在这里，
at the top level,
在顶层，
is going to.only to values which are lower than itself.
只会去寻找比自己小的值。
You are going to go to the next level at the next level.
你将在下一级别上升到下一个级别。
The second level, again,
再次来到第二层，
you are going to look at the numbers of values at that node.
你需要查看该节点的数值数量。
The values are going to go from the smallest battery, c 19,
数值将从最小的电池c 19开始递增。
c 195.
c 195 可以翻译为 "C 195"。
It's against c 195 is greater than c 194.
c 195 大于 c 194 是错误的。
You are going to go again to the next level is going to be allowed,
你将被允许继续进入下一关。
which is pointed out by the first I corresponding to the leftmost value.
这是由第一个指向最左边值的I所指出的。
And finally, here,
最后，在这里，
you are just going to see that you are going to have to find ac 194,
你只需要找到 AC 194 就行了。
so you'll find a match.
所以你会找到一个匹配项。
And that match will take you to the entry in the file directory,
这个匹配项将带你到文件目录中的条目。
which is the name of the file and the file number.
文件的名称是什么？文件的编号是多少？
Michael, here has a great question.
迈克尔，这里有一个很棒的问题。
Why do we want to hash the file names?
为什么我们想要对文件名进行哈希处理？
Wouldn't using the file name themselves in lexicographical order?
是否可以按照文件名的字典顺序进行排序？
Have the benefit that is easy to enumerate files in lexicographical order.
具有按字典顺序轻松枚举文件的优点。
Anyone wants to answer this question?
有人想回答这个问题吗？
The file names can have arbitrary length.
文件名可以有任意长度。
It's going to make the implementation a little bit harder.
这将使实现变得稍微困难一些。
Someone says also perhaps to distribute the hydrogen.
有人也许还建议将氢气分发出去。
For me, that's a great.,
对我来说，这是很棒的。
actually, as well.
实际上，也是如此。
You get the more balanced three.
你得到了更加平衡的三个。
You if you have a hash with hash,
如果你有一个哈希表，
is going to give you pseudo random numbers.
将会为您提供伪随机数。
So you are going to easily get a balance three whiles you once you build it.
一旦你构建好它，你就能轻松地获得一个平衡的三个循环。
But the other thing is that if use of finance, it's their strings.
但另一件事是，如果使用金融，那就是他们的控制权。
So comparing to strings is much more expensive.
所以相比较字符串来说，比较操作更加耗费资源。
Then comparing to numbers again, remember,
再次进行数字比较时，请记住，
we are doing building big trees because we want to improve the performance.
我们正在构建大型树结构，因为我们希望提高性能。
Hash is give you values,
哈希是给你提供值的一种方法，
which are at the end of the day can be our integers,
最终我们可以使用的整数是哪些？
can be.
可以。
And just comparing integers,
仅仅比较整数，
it's much easier.
这样会容易得多。
It's much faster,
它速度更快，
and also much easier to build data structures where the fields have a union
而且使用联合（union）构建数据结构也更加容易。
with the same land.
在相同的土地上。
Do different file systems,
不同的文件系统，
use different between types,
使用不同类型之间的区别
or it's some standard like 234.
或者它是一些标准，比如234。
That's a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
Actually, I do not know the answer to that question.
实际上，我不知道那个问题的答案。
I should look around.
我应该四处看看。
That's a good question.
这是一个很好的问题。
I would assume that there are some a rule of thumb
我会假设有一些经验法则。
here about whether the good numbers for this application.
关于这个应用程序是否有适合的好数字。
While directory can be large,
虽然目录可以很大，
probably it doesn't compare with a number of rows.
可能它不与行数进行比较。
You can have a in a table,
你可以在表格中拥有一个
as you probably know,
正如你可能知道的，
be trees are coming from database field to index the rows in a table.
B树是从数据库字段中获取的，用于对表中的行进行索引。
I guess you can have hundreds of millions or even billions of rows in a table.
我猜你的表格可能会有数亿甚至数十亿行。
I don't as well as a number of files can be large,
我不知道有多少个文件会很大。
is not going to reach that barrier.
不会达到那个障碍。
But that's a good question.
但这是一个很好的问题。
So now we switch gears and we are going to look
所以现在我们要转换方向，我们将要看一下
at another file system and file system,
在另一个文件系统和文件系统中，
its windows and dfs what in distance for new technology?
Windows和DFS在新技术方面有什么区别？
Right?
对吗？
So it's called new technology file system.
所以它被称为新技术文件系统。
It's an interesting name, right?
这是一个有趣的名字，对吧？
Because it's always going to be called new technology,
因为它总是被称为新技术，
but now this is like3020,
但现在是3020年了，
30 years old,
30岁
so cannot be that.
所以不可能是那样的。
So new technology,
新技术，
this is still the default on modern window systems.
这在现代的Windows系统中仍然是默认设置。
And if you are using the windows machine,
如果你正在使用Windows机器，
most likely you are using an ndfs file system.
很可能你正在使用一个NDFS文件系统。
Let me just tell you what is the main idea here.
让我简单告诉你这里的主要思想是什么。
The main idea here,
这里的主要思想是，
one of the main ideas is that instead of fixed blocks,
其中一个主要思想是，不使用固定块，
will we have valuable length blocks?
我们会有有价值的长度块吗？
These variable line blocks are called extents.
这些变量行块被称为extent。
And then instead of the fact or I not array,
然后，不是使用事实或者我不是数组，
we are having here what is called a master file paper.
我们这里正在进行所谓的主文件论文。
And the master file table is almost like a database.
主文件表几乎就像一个数据库。
And it's in the database because it's it has attribute value pairs.
它在数据库中是因为它具有属性值对。
And these attributes and the values can be different things.
这些属性和值可以是不同的东西。
Each of these entries,
每个条目，
which is attribute value,
属性值是什么？
can have one kilobyte size.
可以有一千字节的大小。
So it's more general than the name finding pairs,
因此，它比寻找配对名称更为普遍。
which are finding in traditional file systems.
传统文件系统中常见的功能包括：
Like we learned so far.
就像我们迄今所学的那样。
Let me show you a little bit how this is organized.
让我给你展示一下这是如何组织的。
But the point is that the reason it's more complex,
但关键是它更复杂的原因是，
but this complexity buys your efficiency and performance.
但是这种复杂性换来了您的效率和性能。
And you'll see how one is.
你会看到其中一个是如何的。
If you can find enough room on the disk,
如果您在磁盘上找到足够的空间，
and you can have an extent,
你可以拥有一个扩展。
let's say, of 100 kilobytes larger than any block.
假设有一个比任何块都大100千字节的块。
Right?
对吗？
100 kilobytes extend or even higher,
100千字节或更高的扩展容量，
and that's contiguous.
而且这是连续的。
Right?
对吗？
So it's very fast to read that block.
所以读取该块非常快速。
There is no signal that extent.
没有信号延伸的迹象。
There is no sick time.
没有病假时间。
You have only one sick time.
你只有一次病假。
You need to waste in order to get to that extent.
为了达到那种程度，你需要浪费时间。
But then you read 100 kilobytes with blocks.
然后你使用块大小读取了100千字节。
It's again, it's like they may not be contiguous.
这又是一样的情况，它们可能不是连续的。
So you are going to have more sick times.
所以你将会有更多的病假时间。
And this kind of, it's more complex.
而这种情况，它更加复杂。
And not only that,
不仅如此，
but as you'll see, like, for instance,
但是你会看到，比如说，
if you have a smaller file which is more than one kilobyte,
如果你有一个小于一千字节的文件，
you can actually put in this master file table,
你实际上可以将其放入主文件表中。
because one of these entries, remember,
因为其中一个条目，记住，
it can be a up to one kilobyte.
它可以达到一千字节。
Okay.
好的。
Let's look, this is a master file table,
让我们来看一下，这是一个主文件表。
and then you have a bunch of records.
然后你有一堆记录。
And these records are content depends on how large is a fire.
这些记录的内容取决于火灾的规模有多大。
You also are going to learn next lecture about journaling,
下一堂课你还将学习有关日志记录的内容。
which is a way to provide file reliability for the facts.
提供文件可靠性的一种方式是使用冗余备份。
This is a very small,
这是一个非常小的，
it's a small file,
这是一个小文件，
tiny file.
小文件。
So the file is less than one kilobyte.
所以这个文件小于一千字节。
One of these centuries is one kilobyte.
其中一个世纪是一千字节。
So what do you have here?
那么你在这里有什么问题？
You have in one of these entries in the master file table for these small files.
您在主文件表中有一个条目，用于这些小文件之一。
You have standard information,
您有标准信息。
which is the usual when the file was created or the modified the last time,
通常情况下，指的是文件的创建时间或最后修改时间。
if you wanna access the last time,
如果你想要访问上一次的时间，
owner id some security specify as flags,
owner id 一些安全性指定为标志位。
whether is read only hidden,
是否为只读隐藏。
whether you can see, like,
你能看到吗，比如说，
if you do like a user alice,
如果你喜欢一个名叫Alice的用户，
whether he sees a file or not,
无论他是否看到文件，
or it's a system file and things like that.
或者它是一个系统文件之类的东西。
Right?
对吗？
So this is what you have in the standard information.
这是您在标准信息中所拥有的内容。
Then you have the file name in the file table, master file table.
然后你在文件表中有文件名，主文件表。
You have the file and remember that.
你有这个文件，记住了。
In the case of I node fa you do not have,
在I节点fa不存在的情况下，
you have only I know the I node,
你只需要知道 I 节点即可。
which is a file number.
这是一个文件编号。
The file name is in the directory only.
文件名仅在目录中。
Then like we discuss if the data is a fairly small,
那么就像我们讨论的那样，如果数据相对较小，
you may be able to put the entire data in this entry,
您可以将所有数据放入此条目中。
right?
是的，正确的。
And then it's free.
然后它是免费的。
And you are going to just read on one of all this record.
而你只需要阅读其中一条记录即可。
In one goal,
在一个目标中，
you always want this access.
你总是想要这个权限。
You can read everything about the file, including the data.
您可以阅读文件的所有内容，包括数据。
It's as fast as you can get.
它的速度非常快。
Right.
好的。
Now, what happens if the file is a little bit larger?
现在，如果文件稍微大一些会发生什么情况？
If the file is larger than instead of having the data here,
如果文件太大，而不是将数据放在这里，
right?
对的？
You have A bunch of pointers, attribute values.
你有一堆指针和属性值。
Remember, the same attribute values you are going to have.
请记住，你将拥有相同的属性值。
And each of those is going to point out to a data extent.
每一个都将指向一个数据范围。
Again.
再一次。
Remember, data extend.
记住，数据是可扩展的。
It's a variable size block.
这是一个可变大小的块。
In order to refer to a variable size, block, or extend.
为了引用一个可变大小的变量、块或扩展。
You are going to for to have a a start,
你需要开始了。
aa starting pointer and the length of the extent.
aa的起始指针和范围的长度。
Right?
对吗？
That's enough.
够了。
This is what you have.
这是你所拥有的。
Now, if you have a are there even larger files?
现在，如果你有更大的文件，甚至更大的文件吗？
Then what you have,
那么你有什么需要帮助的？
you can have pointers to there,
你可以有指向它们的指针。
to other extent.
在某种程度上。
Remember to the other mmpf records.
请记得处理其他的mmpf记录。
Remember, at the end of the day, extend,
记住，在一天结束时，延伸。
it's a contiguous region on the disk, right?
是的，它是磁盘上的连续区域。
So these are this leaf.
这些是这片叶子。
No, so to speak in this hierarchy are where the data are,
不，所谓的层次结构中，数据所在的位置是在哪里。
the data extents.
数据范围。
In this particular case,
在这种特殊情况下，
the attribute list is going to.to have to.to different entries
属性列表将会有两个不同的条目。
in the master file table.
在主文件表中。
And this is what a huge file of.
这是一个巨大的文件。
It's again, you are going to have a lot of more mmfd records.
又是这样，你将会有更多的mmfd记录。
Here we go.
我们开始吧。
Right?
对吗？
So basically,
基本上，
at one level, to summarize,
在某种程度上，总结一下，
if the fire is very small,
如果火很小，
the entire file can feed into an mfs mfd record.
整个文件可以输入到一个MFS MFD记录中。
If the file is a little bit larger,
如果文件稍微大一些，
then you still have on one of the mfd record.
那么你仍然在MFD记录中有一个。
But in the instead of data,
但是相反的是数据而不是
you have a bunch of pointers.
你有一堆指针。
They die extent.
他们死亡的程度。
So it's one level of indirection.
所以这是一级间接。
Right?
对吗？
The extents are referred by the start and the leg.
这里的"extents"是指范围的起始和长度。
If the file is even larger,
如果文件更大的话，
then you are going to have multiple mfd records.
那么你将会有多个MFD记录。
And if the file is even larger,
如果文件更大的话，
you're going to have more fmf direction.
你将会有更多的FMF指导。
Directories are implemented as betrays.
目录被实现为树状结构。
Like we learn the file numbers,
就像我们学习文件编号一样，
identify its entry in mft it is similar with the I note table or ra and
识别它在MFT中的条目，它与I节点表或RA相似。
mfd entry always has a file name attribute.
mfd条目始终具有文件名属性。
Right?
对吗？
To remember here, right?
记住这里，对吗？
You can check it.
你可以检查一下。
It's human readable as well.
它也是可读的人类语言。
How do you implement hard link?
硬链接的实现方式是通过在文件系统中创建一个新的目录项，将其与原始文件的inode节点关联起来。这样，原始文件和硬链接文件将共享相同的inode和数据块。当对其中一个文件进行更改时，另一个文件也会受到影响，因为它们指向相同的数据。
要创建硬链接，可以使用命令行工具（如ln命令）或编程接口（如C语言中的link()函数）。创建硬链接时，需要指定原始文件的路径和硬链接文件的路径。在创建硬链接时，需要确保原始文件和硬链接文件位于同一文件系统中。
与软链接不同，硬链接没有指向目标文件的路径，而是直接指向目标文件的inode。这意味着即使原始文件被删除，硬链接文件仍然可以访问和使用目标文件的内容。但是，硬链接只能链接到同一文件系统中的文件，不能跨文件系统链接。
需要注意的是，硬链接只能链接到文件，而不能链接到目录。此外，硬链接不能链接到不存在的文件或目录。
Very simple.
非常简单。
The way you are going to implement a hard link,
你将要实现硬链接的方式是，
that will be another entry in the mfd table,
这将是MFD表中的另一条条目。
which is going to.to the same data extents,
这将访问相同的数据范围。
or is going to point to another mft which represents a file.
或者将指向另一个代表文件的MFT。
Its attribute, least part of the data.
它的属性，数据的最小部分。
This was a question.
这是一个问题。
Very good.
非常好。
I assume that where it's at the good list,
我假设这是在好名单上的地方。
I think it's nice.
我觉得这很好。
Let me just the attribute list, its, again,
让我看一下属性列表，再次确认一下。
is part of the mft record.
是MFT记录的一部分。
I'm not sure what you mean,
我不确定你的意思是什么。
what the question means about asking about whether it's part of the data is
这个问题询问的是关于数据的一部分是否属于其中的一部分。
part of or from afd record for the file.
文件的一部分或来自AFD记录。
And it's, again,
而且，再次提醒，
you have this attribute list if you cannot fit everything in a simple m
如果你无法将所有内容放入一个简单的m中，你可以使用这个属性列表。
in the single mfd record,
在单个 MFD 记录中，
where instead of data,
在这里，数据被替换为
you are going to have pointers to the data extent.
你将会有指向数据范围的指针。
You cannot have this one here in the data part.
你不能将这个放在数据部分。
You do not have enough the room to have to start the pointer,
你没有足够的空间来开始指针。
stall extents.
阻塞范围。
That's great.
太好了。
It's a question here from actually,
这里实际上有一个问题。
what are the pros and cons of this of an assume and dfs over berkeley?
使用Assume和DFS相比于Berkeley的优缺点是什么？
Fast file system?
快速文件系统（Fast File System）？
The list of extensive,
广泛的列表
similar to the list of direct and direct pointers stood in the eye note.
类似于直接和间接指针列表在眼注中的存在。
The data part is replaced with an attribute list of larger facts.
数据部分被替换为一个更大事实的属性列表。
Yeah, do you want to,
是的，你想要什么帮助吗？
anyone would like to answer?
有人愿意回答吗？
So gilbert, you mentioned about the data,
所以 Gilbert，你提到了数据，
but is replaced with the attribute list of four large files.
但是被四个大文件的属性列表所取代。
I'm not sure is that an answer to a shake question?
我不确定这是否是对一个摇一摇问题的回答。
Anyway,
无论如何，
who would like to try to answer this actually question?
谁愿意尝试回答这个实际问题？
What are the pros and cons between ndfs and ffs
NDFS和FFS之间的优缺点是什么？
one thing is about,
有一件事是关于的，
remember,
记住，
what is the difference between extend and blocks reviews enough of us.
"extend" 和 "blocks" 之间有什么区别？"enough of us" 是什么意思？
So with extends,
使用extends关键字，
you can have any size blocks.
你可以拥有任意大小的块。
What ffs gives you is the ability to configure the file system
ffs提供的是配置文件系统的能力。
with different block sizes.
使用不同的块大小。
But once you configure the block size,
但是一旦你配置了块大小，
it will still be the same size.
它仍然会保持相同的大小。
All the blocks are going to be the same size.
所有的块都将具有相同的大小。
And with a data extent,
使用数据范围
with arbitrary size,
具有任意大小的
you are going to be guaranteed that in order to retrieve and to read
您将被保证能够检索和阅读信息。
all the data,
所有的数据，
from one extent,
从某种程度上说，
you are going to have need only one seek to get access to that data.
你只需要进行一次查找就能访问到那些数据。
The blocks are going to be, in general,
一般情况下，这些块将会是
smaller than one extent.
小于一个extent。
You are going to have multiple blocks.
你将会有多个块。
And multiple blocks means that you may have to,
而多个块意味着你可能需要
if they are not contiguous,
如果它们不是连续的，
and you are not guaranteed to be contiguous.
并且不能保证它们是连续的。
If they are blocks,
如果它们是块，
you may have to pay multiple access times to read the same amount of it.
你可能需要支付多次访问时间来读取相同的数据量。
Nfs is also better for small files, exactly.
NFS对于小文件来说也更好，确实如此。
Michael.
迈克尔。
And this be,
这是，
because like you see here,
因为就像你在这里看到的一样，
for if the file is very small,
如果文件非常小，
it's less than one kilobyte,
它小于一千字节。
then it fits in one mfd record.
那么它适合一个MFD记录中。
While in the previous case,
在前面的情况下，
you need to have multiple access to loud,
你需要同时对音量进行多重访问。
a small file, at least.
至少一个小文件。
You need to go to read from I node.
你需要从 I 节点中读取数据。
You need to go to read the data blog, which is separate.
你需要去阅读数据博客，它是独立的。
Like this is a cumulant.
这是一个累积量。
Like the data itself will be part of the eye not.
数据本身将成为眼睛的一部分。
Right?
对吗？
But with ffs is not,
但是使用ffs不是这样的。
you need to read the I node which is access.
你需要读取正在访问的I节点。
And then even have very tiny file,
然后即使有非常小的文件，
you still need to need read another blog where the data is located.
你仍然需要阅读另一个博客，其中包含数据的位置。
Excellent.
非常好。
Now, let's move and do something even more interesting.
现在，让我们继续前进，做一些更有趣的事情吧。
Memory mapped files.
内存映射文件。
Let's what are the memory map files?
内存映射文件是什么？
You see, and why do we need those?
你看，我们为什么需要它们呢？
You see,
你看，
when you access a file and what we learned,
当你访问一个文件时，我们学到了什么？
things are getting quite complicated,
事情变得相当复杂了，
and the data is replicated multiple places from that file.
数据从该文件复制到多个位置。
You need to.
你需要。
The operating system has to have a buffer.
操作系统必须具备缓冲区。
We are going to learn more about the buffer a little bit later to store
我们稍后会更深入地学习关于缓冲区的知识，以便进行存储。
the data in that buffer.
那个缓冲区中的数据。
And then there is another buffer to put that data at the application level.
然后在应用程序级别还有另一个缓冲区来存放这些数据。
You have multiple copies of the data plus system costs.
您拥有多个数据副本以及系统成本。
But what if we could map an entire file directly with our memory?
但是如果我们能够直接将整个文件映射到内存中呢？
Right?
对吗？
And when you are going to read something from that file,
当你要从那个文件中读取内容时，
it just is like you read from that region of memory.
就好像你从内存的那个区域读取一样。
When you have to write it,
当你需要写它时，
you're writing like in memory.
你写得就像在内存中一样。
And eventually,
最终，
the operating system will take care to write back your changes to the list.
操作系统会负责将您的更改写回到列表中。
By the way,
顺便说一下，
the executable files are treated this way when we are executing a process.
当我们执行一个进程时，可执行文件会被这样处理。
So now to see the differences,
现在来看一下区别。
let's refresh our memory about what happens on a page.
让我们回顾一下页面上发生的事情。
47 instruction.
47条指令。
The instruction provides a virtual address.
该指令提供了一个虚拟地址。
The virtual address goes through an mmu and you are going to get
虚拟地址经过内存管理单元（MMU）处理，然后你将获得
the physical page number.
物理页号。
Then you are going to the figure the page number,
那么你需要确定页码。
the physical page number is going to index into a base table.
物理页号将用于索引基表。
Right?
对吗？
And the base table is going to give you the frame number.
基本表将提供给您帧号。
The frame number is going to be,
帧号将会是，
depending whether you are going to have paging or segmentation,
根据你是否要使用分页或分段，
you are going to concatenate a frame number is the offset,
你将要将帧号与偏移量连接起来。
and you are going to get the address of the physical number.
你将获得物理地址的位置。
You go virtual address,
你进入了虚拟地址，
you get the page number from the virtual address is going to point
你可以从虚拟地址中获取页码。
in the page table,
在页面表中，
is going to give you the frame number.
将会给你帧号码。
And then you are going to get the offset of the visual address.
然后你将获取视觉地址的偏移量。
And you are going to get a frame and offset congratulating.
你将获得一张帧和偏移量的祝贺。
You're going to give you the address in the physical memory.
你将会给出物理内存中的地址。
Now, if you are going to have aa baseball,
现在，如果你要参加一场棒球比赛，
baseball means that they do not find the entry
baseball 意味着他们找不到入口
corresponding to the page number is a page type.
对应于页码的是页面类型。
What we are going to do is there is an exception which
我们要做的是处理一个异常，这个异常是...
is going to be handled by the operating system,
将由操作系统处理。
in particular by the baseball handler.
特别是由棒球处理者完成的。
And that is going to look gate on the disk what the page
这将在磁盘上以什么样的页面形式显示？
and is going to load it in memory.
并且将要将其加载到内存中。
Maybe for loading that page,
也许是为了加载那个页面，
you need to evict an existing page,
你需要驱逐一个已存在的页面。
because maybe the memory is full.
可能是因为内存已满。
And then you are going to update the page table to. to the page,
然后你将更新页表，将页表指向页面。
which you just loaded in memory.
你刚刚加载到内存中的程序。
And then you return from the page fault.
然后你从页面错误返回。
And the operators operating system will reschedule that process,
操作系统将重新调度该进程，
which causes a baseball to execute the same instruction.
这会导致棒球执行相同的指令。
And when you execute the same instruction,
当你执行相同的指令时，
now you do have page table is correct.
现在你的页表是正确的。
So you are going to be able to read the page from the physical memory.
所以你将能够从物理内存中读取页面。
So we did that in the past.
我们过去确实做过这件事。
This is just a refresher.
这只是一个复习。
Now, what happens is a memory map as well, very simple.
现在，发生的是一个内存映射，非常简单。
It's exactly what you expect.
这正是你所期望的。
Here it's a file on the disk.
这是一个存储在磁盘上的文件。
You are going just to map the file in the memory,
你只需要将文件映射到内存中。
and you are going to map to initialize the base that we
而你将要映射以初始化我们的基址
are going to allocate base table entries for each page of the file.
将为文件的每个页面分配基本表项。
When you have, in this case, a baseball,
在这种情况下，当你拥有一个棒球时，
basically,
基本上，
when you are going that the page is not in memory which represent a file,
当你访问一个不在内存中的页面时，它可能代表一个文件。
which is part of the file,
这是文件的一部分。
then you are going to load directly the file,
那么你将直接加载文件。
the portion of the file into the page.
将文件的部分内容放入页面中。
And now you are just going to read files when you access it,
现在当你访问它时，你只需要读取文件。
when you access a physical memory,
当你访问物理内存时，
you basically access the content of the file.
你基本上是访问文件的内容。
So this is a i'll give you an example.
所以这是一个例子。
So hopefully that will clarify things.
希望这样能够澄清事情。
This is a system call to create a memory map file.
这是一个用于创建内存映射文件的系统调用。
This basically,
基本上，
you provide the file descriptor of the file and the offset from where you
您提供文件的文件描述符和偏移量，从哪里开始。
want to get to map the data from the file.
想要将文件中的数据映射到地图上。
For instance, if offset it's 100,
例如，如果偏移量为100，
this means that I want to map of starting with a byte,
这意味着我想要从一个字节开始进行映射。
100 from the file into memory.
将文件中的100个数据加载到内存中。
These are some flags and protection.
这些是一些标志和保护措施。
The other very important fields are the address and of the length is
另外两个非常重要的字段是地址和长度。
how much from the file you want to map in memory.
你想要将文件映射到内存中的大小是多少？
And the address,
地址是：
you can even give an address.
你甚至可以提供一个地址。
And if you give an address,
如果你提供一个地址，
then the file system is going to try to map the file that the address is given.
然后文件系统将尝试映射给定地址的文件。
But if it cannot,
但如果它不能的话，
then it may find another place in the physical memory,
然后它可能会在物理内存中找到另一个位置，
which enough space to map the file,
足够的空间来映射文件
which basically is a contiguous region of lang claire.
这基本上是一个连续的克莱尔语区域。
In either way,
无论哪种方式，
the function returns the address in the memory where you map the file.
该函数返回映射文件在内存中的地址。
In most of the cases,
在大多数情况下，
this can be all you can use also this memory map,
这是你可以使用的全部内容，你也可以使用这个内存映射。
also to communicate between processes.
还可以用于进程间通信。
We'll talk briefly about that later.
我们稍后会简要讨论这个问题。
But here is a pro, it.
但是这里有一个问题，它是什么？
Here is an example of a program.
这是一个程序的示例。
We just give you a sense and what memory map files means.
我们只是给你一个概念，以及内存映射文件的含义。
And what is that?
那是什么？
In effect,
实际上，
here is a simple program.
这是一个简单的程序。
And just for the sake of it,
仅仅为了这个目的，
we are going to type three addresses to bring three addresses.
我们将输入三个地址来获取三个地址。
One is something is the address of something is variable something.
一个是某个东西的地址是变量的东西。
And that are something is when a it's a data segment,
当它是一个数据段时，那就是某个东西。
then we are going to allocate something and everything which is allocated.
然后我们将分配一些东西，并分配所有已分配的内容。
It's on the hip.
它在臀部上。
This is address for the result of ma log is residing the hip.
这是存储着我的日志结果的地址。
The last one is to have this my file here variable,
最后一个是拥有这个"my file here"变量。
which is a local variable.
这是一个局部变量。
We know that the local variables of the functions are put on the stack.
我们知道函数的局部变量被放在栈上。
This address depends on is an address in the stack sector.
这个地址依赖于栈区的一个地址。
Then you open a file,
然后你打开一个文件，
and this is a file.
这是一个文件。
We want to map in the memory.
我们想要在内存中进行映射。
And now we map the file in the memory.
现在我们将文件映射到内存中。
Basically, we are taking this file description.
基本上，我们正在处理这个文件描述。
It's file descriptor are going to pass to a map,
它的文件描述符将被传递给一个映射。
the file descriptor of rfd zero,
rfd zero 的文件描述符
meaning that I want to start mapping from the first bite in the file.
意思是我想从文件的第一个字节开始进行映射。
Here there are again, some flags about read, write,
这里有一些关于读取和写入的标志位。
and this is about whether this can be shared between different processes.
这个问题是关于这个是否可以在不同的进程之间共享。
The other important thing is that I am the first address or to map.
另一个重要的事情是，我是第一个地址或映射的对象。
This program passes sets as being zero system,
这个程序将集合作为零系统传递。
the operating system.
操作系统。
You are free to choose a region of memory in the memory where to map this file.
你可以自由选择内存中的一个区域来映射这个文件。
Most of the cases is what you are going to give.
大多数情况下，你要提供的是什么。
This argument will be zero, right?
这个参数将会是零，对吗？
Because you don't know better than the operating system where you
因为你不比操作系统更了解自己
should put this file,
应该把这个文件放在哪里？
or you should put this file in memory.
或者你应该将这个文件放入内存中。
My file is a return,
我的文件是一个返回文件。
the starting address allocated for that file to be mapped,
分配给该文件映射的起始地址
where the map where the file is mapped to.
文件映射到的内存地址。
So now,
现在，
and then you print the file,  Right?
然后你打印这个文件，对吗？
You pass a file.
你传递了一个文件。
This is the argument is an argument of this program, and you print it.
这是程序的一个参数，你需要将其打印出来。
And then you write something at the address of the file in memory+10.
然后你在内存中文件的地址+10的位置写入一些内容。
Let's write over it.
让我们覆盖它。
Let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
First of all, when I print it,
首先，当我打印它时，
this is when you print the file.
这是当你打印文件时的情况。
Let's say this is a question.
假设这是一个问题。
This is the content of the file.
这是文件的内容。
Right?
对吗？
So it's my bad.
这是我的错。
So the first three lines,
所以前三行，
so i'm invoking this program with argument tests.
所以我正在使用参数 "tests" 调用这个程序。
The first three lines are the printers I talk about printing addresses
前三行是我所说的打印机打印地址的内容。
in the data segment,
在数据段中，
heap or stack and stack.
堆或栈和堆栈。
And then the last the next five lines are written by the spring types,
然后接下来的五行是由弹簧类型的人写的。
and is basically the content of the test file.
这基本上就是测试文件的内容。
So the content of the test files that are four lines.
测试文件的内容是四行。
This is line one, line two, line three, and line four.
这是第一行，第二行，第三行和第四行。
Here, i'm now this file,
我现在在这个文件里。
every content the content is mapped in memory.
每个内容都被映射到内存中。
And now in memory,
现在在内存中，
I like I mentioned,
正如我之前提到的，
I am writing at the address+20.
我正在地址+20处写入数据。
Let's write over it.
让我们覆盖它。
And then I close a file.
然后我关闭一个文件。
I want to see what is inspire after I close it.
我想在关闭它之后看看有什么启发。
I look at the test,
我看了一下考试。
and this is what I find.
这是我找到的内容。
This is line one.
这是第一行。
And then you can see,
然后你就可以看到，
let's write over it.
让我们覆盖它。
Because this means that obviously I wrote starting from
因为这意味着显然我是从...开始写的
the The 21st character in the file,
文件中的第21个字符是：
I wrote the string let's write over,
我写了字符串"let's write over"。
which is exact, and then I close a file.
哪个是准确的，然后我关闭文件。
And obviously,
显然，
everything was saved,
一切都已保存，
including the changes in this fact.
包括这个事实的变化。
Does it make sense?
这有意义吗？
It's pretty cool.
这很酷。
You guys should drive.
你们应该开车。
It's like I mentioned,
就像我之前提到的那样，
you can share the files between two different processes.
你可以在两个不同的进程之间共享文件。
Here I have the same file and I have two virtual addresses from two processes.
这里我有同一个文件，并且我有来自两个进程的两个虚拟地址。
You can share,
你可以分享。
you can map the file in memory and can be shared this file
你可以将文件映射到内存中，并且可以共享这个文件。
between these two processes is exactly like a the
这两个进程之间的关系就像一个
file on the disk can be shared between different processes.
磁盘上的文件可以在不同进程之间共享。
Also, you can use this a map to as to share the data,
此外，你可以使用这个地图来共享数据。
or is it to share memory and use a memory to share the data
还是说它是为了共享内存并使用内存来共享数据？
between the parent and the children and your four kids children?
在父母和子女之间以及你的四个孙辈之间？
You can also create an mf file, its anonymous file,
你也可以创建一个mf文件，它是一个匿名文件。
because there is not a real file.
因为没有一个真实的文件。
And you can share it to the children.
你可以把它分享给孩子们。
And then you can use it to pass data between the children and the parents
然后你可以使用它在子进程和父进程之间传递数据。
with this memory map,
使用这个内存映射表，
file anonymous memory.
匿名内存文件。
My fact,
我的事实，
this is not backed by the disk.
这不是由磁盘支持的。
The question here is a file printed by the printer or the puts
这里的问题是文件是由打印机打印还是通过puts输出的。
here is printed by the printer,
这是由打印机打印出来的。
this file.
这个文件。
But I it puts this a special case of printer.
但是这是一个特殊的打印机情况。
Free sprinter fits is formatting, right?
免费的Sprinter适用于格式化吗？
You can bring different values,
你可以带来不同的价值。
right?
对的？
In the same instruction.
在同一条指令中。
Here you can see,
在这里你可以看到，
as a first argument,
作为第一个参数，
you are going to print because you are painting the map address.
你将要打印，因为你正在绘制地图地址。
And the second argument,
第二个参数，
you are printing what is as the address of, i'm fine.
你正在打印的是地址，我没问题。
There what you have?
你有什么东西？
A bunch of you basically have aaa bunch of characters.
你们基本上有一堆字符。
You have a string,
你有一个字符串，
and you print everything what you find that.
并且你打印出你找到的一切。
Okay.
好的。
So announcements of project three,
关于项目三的公告，
design document, remember,
设计文档，记住，
is due saturday,
截止日期是星期六。
this saturday,
这个星期六，
and the homework five,
还有第五次作业，
homework five is due on monday.
作业五的截止日期是星期一。
Basically,
基本上，
almost what2 weeks from now.
距离现在差不多还有两周。
Any questions about memory map files?
关于内存映射文件有什么问题吗？
The next thing we are going to go over is a buffer cache.
接下来我们要讲解的是缓冲区缓存。
Remember, we discussed that when you read from a file,
记住，我们讨论过当你从文件中读取时，
you will create different copies.
你将创建不同的副本。
One of these copies is in the buffer cache.
其中一份副本位于缓冲区缓存中。
It's in the operating system can maintain a cache of the data from the file.
操作系统可以维护文件数据的缓存。
In this case,
在这种情况下，
you can put the data,
你可以存储数据。
you can put I nodes,
你可以放置i节点。
directory,
目录
directories, and so forth.
目录，等等。
And some of these pages which are cashed,
还有一些被缓存的页面，
can be dirty, obviously.
可以变得脏，显然。
And then the operating system has to take care that to write
然后操作系统必须确保进行写入操作的处理
back eventually the dirty pages to the disk.
最终将脏页写回磁盘。
And really, what you want, the key idea,
实际上，你想要的是关键思想。
why do you want to cache the disc data into memory?
为什么要将磁盘数据缓存到内存中？
Again, this is an operating system memory.
这是一个操作系统的内存。
It's not in the user space memory, like memory,
它不在用户空间内存中，类似于内存，
my files you copied directly in the user space.
你直接将我的文件复制到了用户空间。
For this is in the operating system to get this data,
这是在操作系统中获取这些数据的方法。
even if it's in the memory of the operating system,
即使它在操作系统的内存中，
you still need to make a fund,
你仍然需要进行一次资金筹集。
a system called to get that data.
一个被称为的系统来获取那些数据。
And you,
而你，
obviously, you cash it to exploit the locality.
显然，你要将其现金化以利用局部性。
Right?
对吗？
There are more, many access is to the same blocks.
有更多的访问，许多访问是对相同的块进行的。
If you have them in memory is much faster than accessing the disk.
如果你将它们存储在内存中，访问速度比访问磁盘快得多。
You need to do this translation between a bass name of the file and the I nodes.
你需要在文件名和I节点之间进行这个翻译。
And then from the block address to the misconduct, right?
然后从块地址到不当行为，对吗？
The logical block addresses,
逻辑块地址，
let's see how the buffer cache is worked,
让我们来看看缓冲区缓存是如何工作的。
and here is settings up.
这是设置的步骤。
So this is on the right hand side, you have the disk.
所以在右手边，你有磁盘。
This is like ffs layout on the disk.
这类似于磁盘上的ffs布局。
And now this is a buffer cache,
现在这是一个缓冲区高速缓存。
and the buffer cash has a bunch of blocks.
缓冲区中有许多数据块。
The blocks typically are the same size as pages memory, bates.
块通常与页面内存的大小相同，贝茨。
Then you are going to catch the blocks and you can have data blocks.
然后你将捕捉这些块，并且可以获得数据块。
Like I mentioned, they can be I nodes.
就像我之前提到的，它们可以是i节点。
They can be directory innovation.
它们可以是目录创新。
You have a free also,
你也有空。
you can have the free bit map.
你可以使用免费位图。
Remember, you do have the free map on the disk to maintain data about
请记住，你确实有免费的磁盘上的地图来维护有关数据的信息。
what are the available blocks,
可用的块有哪些？
free of available three blocks.
可用的三个块是空闲的。
This is what you have.
这是你所拥有的。
This is a block side is the cache is organized as an array of blocks.
这是一个块侧的缓存，它被组织成一个块数组。
The color represents different kinds of types of information.
颜色代表不同类型的信息。
Here you have a state whether,
这里有一个状态天气报告。
in this case, it's free or dirty or things like that or what happens,
在这种情况下，是免费的还是脏的或类似的东西，或者会发生什么情况？
whether you read or write a blog.
你是否阅读或撰写博客。
Then let's see what happens.
那么让我们看看会发生什么。
Let's say I am reading an I node,
假设我正在读取一个I节点，
sorry, I am reading a a data block.
抱歉，我正在读取一个数据块。
I'm reading a data block,
我正在读取一个数据块。
a new data block from the disk.
从磁盘中获取一个新的数据块。
I am going to find an available block in the cache.
我将在缓存中寻找一个可用的块。
Then I am going to write,
那么我就开始写了。
now you see the state is read.
现在你看到的状态是读取状态。
This means that now I am reading the data from the block on the disk
这意味着现在我正在从磁盘上的块中读取数据。
into this available space.
填入这个可用空间。
Then once you did you once you read it,
然后一旦你读完了它，
you are going to mark that it's no longer free.
你将要标记它不再免费。
If you write it, you have to market that is a dirty.
如果你写了它，你就必须将其营销出去，这是不光彩的。
Because now this is modified.
因为现在这个已经被修改了。
It's no longer the same content as the sale as a page on the disk.
这不再是与磁盘上的页面销售相同的内容了。
Now you say you are going to read a directory,
现在你说你要读取一个目录，
right?
对的？
Is the same thing.
是同一件事。
You are, okay?
你好吗？
You find an available block and you read it there.
你找到一个可用的块，并在那里读取它。
Right?
对吗？
And you say what it is.
你说一下它是什么。
I know,
我知道。
if you do it, the data is the same thing.
如果你这样做，数据是一样的。
But if you write it, now you say dirty,
但是如果你写下来，现在你说脏话，
the data is dirty.
数据是脏的。
This is what if you write in the block?
这是你在块中写的内容？
If you write to a block, you first,
如果你要写入一个块，首先，
if the block is not in the cache,
如果块不在缓存中，
you bring the block in the cache,
你将块带入缓存中，
and you write on the block in the block, on the cache, in memory.
你在块中写入块，在缓存中写入，在内存中写入。
And your market.
以及你的市场。
Is that any questions?
有任何问题吗？
So discussion?
所以是讨论吗？
So the buffer cache is entirely implemented in the operating system.
所以缓冲区缓存完全由操作系统实现。
Right?
对吗？
It's in the software.
这是在软件中。
There is no dlb the blocks goes through transitional
没有双重缓冲区，块通过过渡状态。
state between 3 and years being greeted from the disk,
从磁盘读取的状态在3年之间被问候。
being written to the disk,
正在被写入磁盘中，
and so forth.
等等，诸如此类。
And blocks contains all this variable where variety of information,
并且块包含了所有这些变量，其中包含了各种信息。
like I mentioned,
正如我之前提到的，
I nodes and data and directories and the free math.
I节点、数据、目录和空闲空间管理。
And the os it is going to maintain the manners them to maintain the pointer
操作系统将维护指针的方式来维护它们的行为。
into them.
进入它们。
It's also the os is going to manage this buffer cash when the process exits,
当进程退出时，操作系统还将管理这个缓冲区缓存。
when writes reads.
当写入时，进行读取操作。
For instance, on the process exits,
例如，当进程退出时，
you are going to flush to write back all the modified data
你将执行刷新操作，将所有修改后的数据写回
from the buffer cache to the list.
从缓冲区缓存到列表中。
Now this is a cache, it can fill up.
现在这是一个缓存，它可以填满。
So what happens when you fill up?
当你填满时会发生什么？
There is a replacement policy,
有一个替换策略，
like we know, like the man beijing, if you remember,
就像我们所知道的，就像那个北京的男人，如果你还记得的话，
deployments policy, what can you do?
部署策略，你能做什么？
You can do a radio.
你可以做一个收音机。
It worked pretty well for demand bailing,
对于需求分拣来说，它运行得相当不错。
so I wanna do something like this.
所以我想做类似这样的事情。
This works well.
这个运行得很好。
And if the memory is big enough,
如果内存足够大，
especially if can accommodate the working set of the particular
尤其是如果能够容纳特定工作集的话
applications or consent in terms of the data which is accessed from the file.
在访问文件时，涉及到数据的应用或同意。
Now, the disadvantage is that is for some access patterns,
现在的缺点是对于某些访问模式来说，
you is not good.
你不好。
For instance,
例如，
if i'm just going to scam the file,
如果我只是要欺骗文件，
i'm just going to read and to read to it.
我只是打算阅读并阅读它。
I'm going to read a blog only once.
我只打算阅读这篇博客一次。
So with alu that block is going to displace another block in the buffer cache.
所以使用ALU，该块将会在缓冲高速缓存中替换另一个块。
But then the block we just was loaded into the cache.
然后刚刚加载的块被存入了缓存中。
I am no longer to access again,
我无法再次访问了。
because I got it later.
因为我后来才明白。
I'm just doing a scan.
我只是在进行扫描。
So that's a problem.
那是个问题。
Right?
对吗？
What is a solution here?
这里的解决方案是什么？
It's a smart solution.
这是一个聪明的解决方案。
The solution here is that the operating system allow application
这里的解决方案是操作系统允许应用程序
to request other policies.
请求其他政策。
The application knows more best.
应用程序最了解。
What is the access pattern?
访问模式是什么？
If the application knows that it's only going to scan the file,
如果应用程序知道它只需要扫描文件，
it can specify as a replacement policy use once.
它可以指定为一次性使用的替换策略。
This means that the file system can discard the block as soon as they are used.
这意味着文件系统可以在使用后立即丢弃这些块。
They don't need to operating system,
他们不需要操作系统。
doesn't need to maintain that block in the buffer cash.
不需要在缓冲区中维护该块。
Now, the cache is obviously stored in the memory.
现在，缓存显然存储在内存中。
One question is that how much memory you should give
一个问题是你应该给多少内存。
to the operating system for the buffer cache versus
对于缓冲区缓存而言，与操作系统相关的
the memory for to map the processes virtual address space.
用于映射进程虚拟地址空间的内存。
If you give too much memory to the file system cache,
如果你给文件系统缓存分配了太多的内存，
the access can be fast,
访问速度可以很快，
but you may not have enough room left for the applications.
但是你可能没有足够的剩余空间来安装应用程序。
If you give too little memory,
如果给予的内存太少，
you are going to have a lot of access to the disk,
你将会对磁盘拥有很多访问权限，
because you cannot cash the blocks which are going to be used.
因为你不能兑现即将使用的区块。
Frequently.
经常。
The solution here in the operating system adjust dynamically is a boundary
操作系统中动态调整的解决方案是一个边界。
between the os cash,
操作系统缓存之间
the application memory,
应用程序内存
so that the amount of the rate of beijing in are roughly the same.
这样北京的利率金额大致相同。
Any questions about
关于计算机操作系统的任何问题都可以问我。
another things about is the file systems.
另一个关于操作系统的内容是文件系统。
You see, a lot is pre fetching,
你知道，很多都是预取操作。
refreshing, you remember is read ahead.
刷新，你记得是预读。
And we discuss that also in the case of demand beijing and demand beijing
我们还讨论了在需求方面的北京和需求方面的北京的情况。
is to avoid compulsory misses.
是为了避免强制缺失。
Right?
对吗？
If the access is sequential,
如果访问是顺序的，
that if you have your one of your access, one block,
如果你拥有其中一个访问权限，一个块，
then you are going to very likely these are data from the next block.
那么很可能这些是来自下一个块的数据。
So why not bring both blocks right away in memory?
那为什么不立即将这两个块都加载到内存中呢？
Right?
对吗？
And avoid to have another access to the disk,
并且避免对磁盘进行其他访问，
which is very expensive.
这非常昂贵。
You have aggression here.
你在这里表现出了攻击性。
How many how much you are going to read ahead?
你打算提前读多少？
How many blocks are you going to prefect?
你打算预读多少个块？
If you do too many,
如果你做得太多，
then it's fine,
那就好，
but you are going to be wasteful.
但这样会浪费资源。
Right?
对吗？
And if you are going to do too little,
如果你打算做得太少，
then you are going to have a lot of more access.
那么你将会有更多的权限。
So not these two things off.
不要关闭这两个东西。
One is be fetching is easy if the blocks are sequentially arrange on the group,
如果数据块在组中按顺序排列，那么获取一个数据块就很容易。
arrange on the disk.
在磁盘上进行排列。
Right?
对吗？
Because it's one sick time,
因为这是一次病假，
and you just read multiple blocks.
而且你只是读取多个数据块。
The other thing,
另外一件事，
it's if you are going,
如果你要去的话，
even if the blocks are not sequential,
即使块不是连续的，
then you are going to provide the disk controller,
那么你将提供磁盘控制器。
a bunch of blocks you want to read.
一堆你想要读取的数据块。
And you remember the elevator algorithm.
你还记得电梯算法吗？
Two lectures ago,
两节课之前，
the elevator algorithms reorder the requests.
电梯算法重新排序请求。
If he gets more requests at the same time,
如果他同时收到更多的请求，
so that he uses the sick time,
以便他使用病假时间。
it puts them in the order in the order along the direction that the head
它按照头部的方向将它们按顺序放置。
is moving.
正在移动。
Excuse me,
请问有什么可以帮到您的吗？
the head it doesn't go back and forth.
头部不会前后移动。
It's just going in one direction,
它只朝一个方向前进。
and is going to get small sick times to the next request,
并且将在下一个请求时变得更加短暂的病假时间。
minimizing the sick time.
减少病假时间。
So the more privileges you do,
所以你拥有的权限越多，
the more requests are going to give the disk,
越多的请求将会发送给磁盘。
the more potential to for the elevator algorithms to be efficient at the
电梯算法越有潜力提高效率
minimize the sick time.
减少病假时间。
So how much to prefect you just discussed?
那么，你刚刚讨论的完善程度需要多少费用？
Too much.
太多了。
It's going to be wasteful boss because delays,
老板，这样做会很浪费，因为会导致延迟。
because it takes maybe a little bit more time to refresh multiple blocks,
因为刷新多个块可能需要更多时间。
but also because they are going to bring this data in in the buffer cache.
而且还因为他们将把这些数据带入缓冲区缓存中。
And maybe you are not going to use it.
也许你不打算使用它。
And this data, the blocks you are not going to use it,
而且这些数据，你不会使用这些块。
May be replaced some blocks you are going,
可能会替换掉一些你正在使用的块。
which are used frequently too little pre fetching,
这些经常使用但预取量过少的操作
many, more six, right?
很多，再加上六个，对吗？
If you at the limit,
如果你达到了极限，
you prefer the only one.
你更喜欢唯一的一个。
You prepare nothing, right?
你什么都没准备，对吗？
You just then you are going to have a sick for each new block.
每当你获得一个新的块时，你就会感到恶心。
You are accessing.
你正在访问。
This was about reading multiple blocks.
这是关于读取多个数据块的问题。
The same you can do also about the rights is called delayed rights.
关于权限，你也可以采取的方法叫做延迟权限。
So delay writes basically means that it's, again,
延迟写入基本上意味着，再次，
when you write the data,
当你写入数据时，
you modify the data is modified only in memory in the buffer cache.
你修改的数据只会在缓冲区高速缓存中的内存中被修改。
So it is not written immediately on the disk.
所以它不会立即写入磁盘。
So therefore, the rights are very fast out of the memory,
因此，数据从内存中读取的速度非常快。
the rise to the file, a rise to memory.
将文件提升到内存中。
If the block is in the buffer cache,
如果块在缓冲区缓存中，
the read is going to first go to the buffer cash to see why there is
读操作首先会访问缓冲区来查看其中的内容。
a block they want to read,
他们想要读取的数据块
which is a buffer cash.
缓冲缓存是什么。
And if it is in,
如果它在的话，
is going to get the most up to date value.
将获得最新的值。
Even if that block was not written yet on the disk,
即使该块尚未写入磁盘，
is still the up.
仍然是最新的。
The right.
正确的。
Previous right update is a block in the memory.
之前的正确更新是内存中的一个块。
So we have to find here.
所以我们在这里找到了。
So when does the right,
所以什么时候是正确的，
the changes made by a right to reach the list?
一个权利对列表进行的更改是什么？
There are a few cases.
有几种情况。
One is operating system is flashing it periodically.
一个操作系统正在定期闪烁。
I think, like, say, 30 seconds,
我觉得，就像，大约30秒。
every 30 seconds,
每30秒，
you go and scan the buffer cache,
你去扫描缓冲区缓存，
and you look at the blocks which are dirty and ride them on the disk.
然后你查看那些脏块并将它们写入磁盘。
Or obviously, when the cash is full,
或者显然，当现金已满时，
then you may want to flush them to write on the disk.
那么你可能想要将它们刷新到磁盘上进行写入。
So what are the delay rights advantages?
延迟权益有哪些优势？
Why don't you tell me here?
为了方便其他学生查阅和参考，我们鼓励在课程论坛上进行讨论和提问。这样可以确保所有学生都能受益，并且可以有更多人参与讨论。如果你有任何问题，请在论坛上提问，我会尽快回复你。谢谢！
What do you think?
你认为呢？
Are the delayed right advantages compared with you right back every time
每次都延迟右转是否比你右转回来有优势？
you want to modify a block?
你想修改一个块吗？
Yes, you do not have to go all the way to the disk for changing every time.
是的，你不需要每次都去访问磁盘进行更改。
That's very good.
非常好。
Can you think about anything else?
你还能想到其他什么吗？
So honest, again, if you don't need to go to the disk,
再次诚实地说，如果你不需要访问磁盘的话，
you are going to have a performance advantage, obviously, because you like,
显然，你会有性能优势，因为你喜欢这个。
I said,
我说过，
you just write a memory to write to the disk.
你只需要编写一个将内存写入磁盘的程序。
Right?
对吗？
It's also,
同样，
you can accumulate multiple rights, right?
你可以累积多个权限，对吗？
You can write to the same block multiple times before you is,
在写入之前，您可以多次写入同一个块。
before you are going to write the block to the disk,
在将数据块写入磁盘之前，
you have only ones right to the disk,
你只有一次访问磁盘的权利。
corresponding to many updates of that block.
对应于该块的许多更新。
The other thing is like for the reads,
另外一件事是关于读取操作，
if you are going to write multiple pages that discuss the same time,
如果你打算写多个页面来讨论同一个主题，
you understand all these requests to the disk and the disks,
你理解所有对磁盘和磁盘的请求。
the elevator algorithms on the disk,
磁盘上的电梯算法
again, reorder these requests,
请再次重新排序这些请求，
so that there is going to write close together,
这样就可以写得更加紧凑了。
blocks one after another,
一个接一个地排列的块
and again, minimize the sector.
再次，将扇区最小化。
Another thing is that for delay rights,
另外一件事是关于延迟权利的。
you may want to allocate multiple blocks at the same time.
你可能想要同时分配多个块。
For a files to keep them contiguous.
为了使文件保持连续。
You can make a room when you write,
你在写作时可以创建一个房间。
you write multiple contiguous files.
你需要写入多个连续的文件。
Right?
对吗？
What i'm trying to say here is that when you are going to write data and I
我想说的是，当你要写入数据时，我建议你使用
have multiple blocks that are modified from or the new blocks,
有多个被修改或新增的块。
right?
对的？
Because you can create new blocks,
因为你可以创建新的块，
which I remember they are not on the disk.
我记得它们不在磁盘上。
If you expand the file, right?
如果你展开这个文件，对吗？
If you're right at the end of the file on the disk is smaller, right?
如果你在磁盘上的文件末尾，那么文件的大小就会较小，对吗？
But now you are going to write,
但是现在你要写了。
you are going to allocate more data in the buffer cache,
你将在缓冲区高速缓存中分配更多的数据。
that now the filing memory is larger than the file of the disk.
现在，文件内存的大小超过了磁盘上的文件。
Now you find out they worth of ten blocks in memory,
现在你发现了内存中十个块的价值。
then if I delay to write these ten blocks to the disk,
那么如果我延迟将这十个块写入磁盘，
when I write them the disk,
当我将它们写入磁盘时，
now are these ten blocks?
现在有这十个块吗？
I'm telling that from the same file,
我是说从同一个文件中，
so maybe you can find a contiguous place to one that needs to place
所以也许你可以找到一个连续的位置来放置那个需要放置的东西。
all these ten blocks,
所有这十个块
one after another,
一个接一个地
which again, is convenient when you read the data from these blocks,
当你从这些块中读取数据时，这再次是很方便的。
because there's one after another,
因为一个接一个地出现，
says particular region on the risk.
指出特定地区的风险。
Again, you avoid, in that case,
在这种情况下，你再次回避了问题。
the boys are sick that we are going to avoid the second rotation like this.
这些男孩生病了，我们要避免进行第二轮这样的活动。
Here is a fun thing.
这是一个有趣的事情。
If you have some files,
如果你有一些文件，
you open a file during we need your application.
在我们需要您的应用程序期间，您打开了一个文件。
And you close it,
然后你关闭它，
you just use from some to have a file to create a file to share some data
你只需要从某个地方获取一个文件，然后创建一个文件来共享一些数据。
between two applications.
两个应用程序之间。
If that file, it's very short duration,
如果那个文件非常短暂的话，
you may never make on the disk, right?
你可能永远不会在磁盘上创建吗？
Because it's going to be removed and it's going to be deleted before closed,
因为它将被移除并在关闭之前被删除。
right?
对的吗？
And delete it before.
然后在之前删除它。
You have the operating system,
你拥有操作系统。
have a chance to write it on the disk.
有机会将其写入磁盘。
Okay, so here I have a question for you.
好的，那么我这里有一个问题要问你。
So with the man beijing,
所以与北京的男人一起吗？
we remember we demand beijing,
我们记得我们要求北京，
we have an aluria and the same kind of algorithms,
我们有一个Aluria和相同类型的算法。
but we are very paranoid then about the performance of the allergy.
但是我们对过敏反应的性能非常担心。
And we implement some approximation like clock algorithms and things like that.
我们实现了一些近似算法，比如时钟算法等等。
Second chance algorithm with buffer caching,
具有缓冲区缓存的"第二次机会"算法
it turns out that people do not implement exact area in the operating system.
事实证明，人们在操作系统中并没有实现精确的区域功能。
So people are not as concerned about the performance of alu cashing
所以人们对ALU缓存的性能不太关注
for buffer for allah,
为了阿拉的缓冲区，
you for buffer cashing versus demand beijing.
缓冲现金与需求北京的比较。
Why do you think is that?
你认为是为什么呢？
Why do you think that in the case of the buffer catching is
为什么你认为在缓冲区捕获的情况下是这样的？
fine to implement the exact area?
实现精确的面积是否可以？
Where is the context of demand?
需求的上下文在哪里？
Paging is not that we need to implement up or smash.
分页不是我们需要实现的上升或粉碎的操作。
It's in softer,
这是更柔软的。
so not that much of a performer skit painting is also in softer.
所以并不是那么多的表演者，绘画也更加柔和。
So demand painting is implemented in software as well.
需求绘制也可以在软件中实现。
Anyone?
有人吗？
I think it's a subtle question and it's okay.
我认为这是一个微妙的问题，没关系。
If you do not the answer to this question,
如果你不知道这个问题的答案，
one reason is about think about the foreign thing,
一个原因是要思考外来的事物。
demand paging,
需求分页
the expectation of the application you are going to read and write from memoir.
你将从备忘录中读取和写入的应用程序的期望。
This is what you are against.
这是你反对的东西。
You are against the latency provided by sort of memory,
你对某种内存提供的延迟持反对态度。
because as the expectation of the application,
因为作为应用程序的期望，
it acts as his memory,
它充当了他的记忆功能。
you need to be very fast.
你需要非常快速。
In contrast,
相比之下，
when you access a file,
当你访问一个文件时，
you don't have a expectation to be that fast.
你不需要期望那么快。
Buffer cash is improving the latency,
缓存提高了延迟。
but the baseline is accessing the disk, which is slow.
但基线是访问磁盘，这是一个较慢的过程。
And sometimes you have to access the disk because it's a buffer
有时候你需要访问磁盘，因为它是一个缓冲区。
that the data is not in memory and so forth.
数据不在内存中等等。
So the fire,
所以火灾，
so that's kind of one reason, right?
所以这算是一个原因，对吗？
Because expectation on you,
由于对你的期望，
when you when you access a disk,
当你访问磁盘时，
is not to have the fastest operations.
不是为了拥有最快的操作。
Right?
对吗？
So therefore, it's okay.
所以，这样做是可以的。
If you had ability to be slower,
如果你有能力变慢一些，
and actually,
实际上，
with being a little bit slower,
稍微慢一点，
you can manage a cash even better,
你可以更好地管理现金。
but it's no longer an approximation algorithm.
但这不再是一个近似算法。
Eviction palette policy demands beijing.
驱逐政策要求北京。
Remember, is you have big not recently used pages when memory is slow,
请记住，当内存较慢时，如果有大量最近未使用的页面，
close to full.
接近满了。
With buffer cash is different if you write back dirty blocks periodically,
如果定期回写脏块，缓冲区的现金流将会有所不同。
even if you recently.
即使你最近才开始。
Why is that?
为什么这样？
The reason for that is, again,
这是因为，再次说一遍，
different expectations.
不同的期望。
When I read and write to memory,
当我读取和写入内存时，
I don't have any expectation about your ability of the data.
我对你处理数据的能力没有任何期望。
Right?
对吗？
You do expect that the computer crashes or even the program crashes,
你确实预计计算机会崩溃，甚至程序会崩溃。
you lose your data in memory, right?
你在内存中丢失了数据，对吗？
But if you're right on the disk,
但是如果你在磁盘上是正确的，
if you think that you're right in a file,
如果你认为你在一个文件中是正确的，
you do assume that what you wrote is persistent.
你假设你所写的内容是持久的。
Right?
对吗？
So now,
所以现在，
we'll talk about this quite a bit for the reminding of this lecture
在本讲座的剩余时间里，我们将会详细讨论这个问题。
and the next lecture.
和下一堂课。
You need the operating system needs to try pretty hard to provide that persistence.
操作系统需要尽力提供持久性。
Savannah is doing it is by periodically writing the updated,
Savannah通过定期写入更新的方式来实现。
modified blocks from the buffer cash is a risk.
从缓冲区高速缓存中修改的块是一种风险。
The marginal difference between al a real and on a normal area.
在实际区域和正常区域之间的边际差异。
Isn't that big in this context since this baseline,
在这个背景下，这并不是很重要。
since the baseline is at these corporations,
由于这些公司是基准，
which takes super long?
哪个花费的时间非常长？
Anyways,
无论如何，
this is a comment by gilbert.
这是Gilbert的评论。
That's exactly correct, right?
这是完全正确的，对吗？
So in the case of the buffer cash,
在缓冲区现金的情况下，
the baseline is a disk.
基准是一个磁盘。
In the case of demand beijing,
在需求方面，北京的情况是这样的，
the baseline is a memo.
基准是一份备忘录。
So like,
所以，就像，
like we mentioned in order to improve the persistency,
正如我们之前提到的，为了提高持久性，
the operating system rise data to the disk from the buffer cash periodically.
操作系统会定期将数据从缓冲区写入磁盘。
So it flashes it,
所以它会闪烁
like in the case of being on 70, 30 seconds.
就像在70号上，30秒的情况下。
However, obviously,
然而，显然，
this is not bulletproof,
这不是百分之百可靠的，
right?
对的？
I what if the operator, the operating system,
我是操作系统的助教，
or you have a failure as a machine fails,
或者你会遇到机器故障导致的失败，
and you have dirty blocks into the buffer cache.
并且你在缓冲区缓存中有脏块。
Obviously, this information is lost.
显然，这些信息已经丢失了。
Right now, you have the case.
现在，你有这个案例。
You have from your application.
你已经通过了你的申请。
You wrote,
你写道，
something is a file you owe,
这里的"something is a file you owe"的意思是"something"是你欠的一个文件。
it was open.
它是开着的。
And now, machine file fails after you wrote.
现在，你写完之后机器文件出现了故障。
And what you wrote is not in the fact.
你所写的并不符合事实。
Although as a programmer,
作为一个程序员，
you may believe that I wrote in a file,
你可能会认为我写在一个文件中，
the file is persistent.
该文件是持久化的。
It must be in a file,
它必须在一个文件中。
because it happened before the failure.
因为它发生在故障之前。
Right?
对吗？
And this can be pretty ugly.
而且这可能会相当丑陋。
If you, for instance, you want to modify a directory.
如果你想修改一个目录，例如。
If you don't modify,
如果你不进行修改，
then you may lose entire files because they are you lost.
那么你可能会丢失整个文件，因为它们已经丢失了。
They are dangling fans.
它们是悬挂的风扇。
There.
好的。
We have no presence in the directory or there are many others.
我们在目录中没有任何存在，或者有很多其他人。
Okay?
好的？
You may lose, I know, and so forth.
你可能会失败，我知道，诸如此类的事情。
So the file system needs some mechanism to ensure the persistence,
因此，文件系统需要一些机制来确保持久性，
including some recovery mechanisms to recover kind of inconsistent state.
包括一些恢复机制来恢复某种不一致的状态。
There are three important properties of a system when it comes to
系统在以下三个方面具有重要特性：
1. Reliability（可靠性）：系统应该能够在长时间运行中保持稳定和可靠的性能。它应该能够正确地执行任务，并且不会出现意外的故障或崩溃。
2. Availability（可用性）：系统应该随时可用，即使在面临故障或错误的情况下也应该能够继续提供服务。它应该能够快速恢复并保持高度可用性，以满足用户的需求。
3. Scalability（可扩展性）：系统应该能够适应不断增长的需求和负载。它应该能够有效地处理更多的用户和数据，而不会影响性能或稳定性。系统的设计和架构应该具有良好的可扩展性，以便随着需求的增加进行扩展。
its to speak,
这是说话的能力。
performance availability and so forth of a system and the file system,
系统和文件系统的性能、可用性等等
in particular.
具体来说。
So there are three things.
所以有三件事情。
One is availability and availability really tells you percentage of time
其中一个是可用性，可用性实际上告诉你时间的百分比。
while the
while循环
system can accept and serve your requests.
系统可以接受并处理您的请求。
So three lines, meaning,
所以三行，意思是，
in this case,
在这种情况下，
meaning that the probability you send a request to the file system and you
这意味着你发送请求到文件系统的概率和你
don't get a reply or it is not resolved,
没有收到回复或问题没有解决。
is 0.1%.
是0.1%。
Then in durability,
然后在耐久性方面，
the durability means is that if the data is on the disk,
耐久性的意思是，如果数据存储在磁盘上，
then is durable,
那么它是耐用的。
meaning that if this fails,
意思是如果这个失败了，
there is still a way to recover the data,
还有一种方法可以恢复数据，
availability and durability.
可用性和耐久性。
They are not the same,
它们不是相同的，
because availability means that the data is somewhere,
因为可用性意味着数据存在于某个地方，
but doesn't mean necessary that it's accessible.
但这并不意味着一定是可访问的。
And then is a reliability is usually the strongest one is the ability
然后可靠性通常是最强的能力。
of a system to better form is required functions as it is defined.
需要对系统进行改进以更好地满足定义的功能要求。
Its application level definition,
应用层定义，
what that means to perform the function and is
这意味着执行该函数是什么意思
typically stronger than because it implies availability.
通常比"因为"更强，因为它暗示了可用性。
If it's not available,
如果不可用，
the the system cannot perform its functions and also includes durability,
系统无法执行其功能，还包括耐久性。
because the data has to be any purses and data.
因为数据必须是任意的钱包和数据。
I should be able to get access to it.
我应该能够获得对它的访问权限。
First, we are going to look about how to make this system,
首先，我们将看一下如何制作这个系统。
the file system durable.
文件系统持久化。
How do you make a file system beautiful?
如何使文件系统变得美观？
What I said that what I want to ensure here is that if I wrote the data
我想要确保的是，如果我写入了数据，
on a disk in a file,
在磁盘上的一个文件中，
I want to get to be able to read that data at a later time,
我希望能够在以后的时间读取这些数据。
no matter what kind of failures were happening.
无论发生什么样的故障。
Right?
对吗？
Say, the one classic failure is that I this failure.
嗯，一个经典的失败案例就是我这个失败。
Ii wrote that on the disk,
我把它写入了磁盘。
it made it from the buffer cash to the disk.
它从缓冲区转移到了磁盘。
But then that's this failed.
但是那样就失败了。
I lost the data.
我丢失了数据。
How do you avoid that?
你如何避免这种情况发生？
Redundancy?
冗余性？
You back up?
你备份好了吗？
Absolutely, is what you are doing for you,
当然，你所做的是为了你自己。
sure you should do for your only the most important data you have,
当然，你应该只备份你拥有的最重要的数据。
right to more than one,
拥有超过一个的权利
this totally.
这完全是这样的。
And there are many ways to do it.
有很多种方法可以做到这一点。
And we'll see you can do it,
我们会看看你能不能做到。
rich solomon.
Rich Solomon. 理查德·所罗门。
They are correcting codes.
他们正在纠正代码。
There are other things you can do.
还有其他事情你可以做。
It is like,
就像是，
you can have battery backgrounds or non volatile ground.
你可以选择电池背景或非易失性接地。
See that doesn't necessarily need to be on the disk.
看到的东西不一定需要存储在磁盘上。
But you can also write it in ram as long as it's powered as in its own battery,
但只要它有自己的电池供电，你也可以将数据写入RAM中。
its own battery,
它自己的电池，
and the machine fails.
机器发生故障。
The ram is not wiped out,
内存没有被清除。
but to clearly to have the data surviving more a lot of more long term,
但为了确保数据能够长期存储更久，
we need to replicate it.
我们需要复制它。
And again, when you replicate it,
再次，当你复制它时，
you need to be very clear about the assumptions,
你需要非常清楚地了解假设条件。
failure assumption you are making.
你所做的失败假设。
Because if you have to these stripes and both are on the same machine,
因为如果你有这些条纹，并且它们都在同一台机器上，
if the machine fails,
如果机器发生故障，
then you lost both copies to avoid that.
那么你就丢失了两份副本以避免这种情况发生。
You need to put copies on different machines.
你需要将副本放在不同的机器上。
But if the machines are in the same rack,
但是如果机器在同一个机架上，
and the rack fails,
当机架发生故障时，
or the data center experience a catastrophic failure,
或者数据中心遭遇灾难性故障，
you lost access to those of copies.
你失去了对那些副本的访问权限。
Now you can put the copies on several different continents.
现在你可以将副本放在几个不同的大陆上。
You are going to be safer than You see that, right?
你会比你想象的更安全，对吗？
Because typically,
由于通常情况下，
many of you assume that when they back up their data,
很多人都假设当他们备份数据时，
where do you back up the data?
你将数据备份在哪里？
Do you back on the same machine?
你是在同一台机器上返回吗？
Now?
现在吗？
Where do you back it up?
你把它备份到哪里？
Actually, I'm curious anyone backs up the data
实际上，我很好奇是否有人备份数据。
cloud,
云计算
many people being the other one clone the cloud.
许多人将云服务作为克隆的对象。
Right?
对吗？
Yeah, and this is Michael has a good point,
是的，Michael说得很有道理，
maybe also the medium you want to write on different media to protect
也许你还想在不同媒体上写作以保护信息。
against some catastrophic failure,
防止一些灾难性故障，
which are going to engage to involve only on media or degradation over time.
这将仅涉及媒体或随时间逐渐恶化。
Good.
好的。
But many people to write to the cloud, right?
但是很多人都会将文件写入云端，对吗？
And the cloud actually can replicate the data across different regions
云服务实际上可以将数据复制到不同的地区
in different continents.
在不同的大陆上。
But now getting back and this was like many years back and this was people
但现在回过头来看，这是很多年前的事情了，那时候的人们...
are developed.
已经开发完成。
First,
首先，
the technology called grade actually was developed at Berkeley by David Patterson,
所谓的GRADE技术实际上是由David Patterson在伯克利开发的。
Randy cards, and their student god Gibson was faculty of Kennedy mellow.
兰迪卡片和他们的学生神吉布森是肯尼迪悠闲的教职员。
Now it's at Toronto.
现在它在多伦多。
Is that Toronto you just have a replica of each disk and one you call
那个多伦多是你刚刚复制了每个磁盘的一个副本，并且你称之为一个。
the recovery group.
恢复小组。
You double the capacity you need and your new rights.
您将所需容量翻倍，同时获得了新的权限。
A write is done only if you write both as the primary and the replica
只有在主节点和副本节点都写入时，才会执行写操作。
of or recovery group.
恢复组或恢复团队。
That's it.
就这样。
Right.
好的。
Now the problem here is that the rights can be quite expensive,
现在的问题是权利可能非常昂贵，
because each right in it needs to go to tourists.
因为其中的每一个权利都需要给游客使用。
And you remember when you write,
你记得当你写的时候，
you have but a rotation,
你只有一个轮换。
a disk latency,
磁盘延迟
you had going now to finish,
你现在要去完成了。
and you are going to wait for the slowest time to finish disk.
你需要等待最慢的时间来完成磁盘操作。
For as long as this to finish,
要完成这个需要多长时间
that was a performance.
那真是一场精彩的表演。
It's worse for rights.
权利方面更糟糕。
You can synchronize the disks.
你可以同步磁盘。
Right?
对吗？
So then all both of them finish at the same time.
那么两者都同时完成。
But that's very hard.
但那很难。
What about the reads?
读取方面呢？
It turns out that with these, you are better, right?
原来用这些的话，你会更好，对吧？
Because with reads,
因为使用读取操作，
actually,
实际上，
you can have twice a boundaries because you can read for any replicas,
你可以有两倍的边界，因为你可以读取任何副本。
right?
是的，正确的。
Or you can send the same read to both replicas,
或者你可以将相同的读请求发送给两个副本，
and you get the one which is arrived first.
然后你会得到先到达的那个。
So it's good for reads.
所以对于读取操作来说是不错的。
Both in terms of latency and the support is bad for rights.
无论是延迟还是支持权限方面，都很糟糕。
And also we need to double the capacity.
而且我们还需要将容量翻倍。
What happens on the recovery?
恢复过程中会发生什么？
When a disk fails,
当磁盘发生故障时，
you need to buy a new disk.
你需要购买一块新的硬盘。
Then you are going to copy the data to the new disk,
然后你将把数据复制到新的磁盘上。
all data to the new disk.
将所有数据复制到新的磁盘上。
Now you have a game to Africa's.
现在你有一个关于非洲的游戏。
Now, that was, again, pretty expensive.
现在，又是相当昂贵的。
And that was the right one.
那个是正确的。
Again, right,
再次，正确的，
is means redundant arrays of inexpensive disks,
RAID（冗余磁盘阵列）是指廉价磁盘的冗余阵列。
as opposed to much more expensive,
相比较更昂贵的情况下，
presumably more reliable beasts.
可以推测这些动物更加可靠。
Here you have cheap,
这里有便宜的，
less reliable this,
不太可靠
but because you do this kind of replication or you'll see a major coding,
但是如果你这样复制，或者你会看到一个主要的编码问题。
you are going to achieve a much higher level,
你将会达到一个更高的水平。
given a much higher reliability than the expense of these.
相比于这些费用，提供更高的可靠性。
There are different, again, level levels of rare rage.
稀有愤怒有不同的层级。
And you can look in the textbook.
你可以查阅教科书。
They five and more what they do.
他们做的事情超过五个以上。
They basically,
基本上，他们
they stripe the data across multiple disks,
他们将数据分散存储在多个磁盘上，
and they add also a paradise,
他们还添加了一个天堂，
a a parody law.
一个恶搞法律。
So basically say, in this case,
所以基本上说，在这种情况下，
in this figure,
在这个图中，
that each DD one, d two, d three,
每个DD一个，D两个，D三个。
these are disks, and these are the blocks.
这些是磁盘，这些是块。
D zero, d one, d two, d three.
D 零，D 一，D 二，D 三。
Sorry.
抱歉。
These are the blocks, the name of the blocks, d zero, d one, d two, d three.
这些是块，块的名称是 d zero、d one、d two、d three。
Then to this one,
那么对于这个问题，
you are going to add a parity block is zero.
你将要添加一个奇偶校验块，其值为零。
The one you can do it.
你是可以做到的。
The p zero is the x or of the values of the data blocks.
p zero是数据块值的逻辑或运算结果。
Therefore, you have four data blocks.
因此，您有四个数据块。
You are going to add another one,
你要再添加一个吗？
which is a paradigm.
这是一个范式。
The overhead here is 25%,
这里的开销是25%。
not doubled.
不是加倍的。
What happens here?
这里发生了什么事情？
You can,
你可以。
if one this goes away,
如果其中一个消失了，
you can still reconstruct the data.
你仍然可以重建数据。
How do you do it?
你是如何做到的？
You reconstruct the data of the lost block by simple x sorry,
你可以通过简单的 x 来重建丢失块的数据。
all the remaining blocks,
所有剩余的块，
the three remaining blocks,
剩下的三个块，
plaza, parity block.
广场，奇偶校验块。
It's as simple as that.
就是这么简单。
You can also spread the Information,
你也可以传播这些信息，
not only across multiple disks in the same server or in the same data center.
不仅限于在同一台服务器或同一数据中心的多个磁盘之间。
You can also do it across the internet.
你也可以通过互联网来完成。
You can use the same technique.
你可以使用相同的技术。
I'm going to stop here.
我要停在这里了。
We are going to talk a little bit more about this,
我们将会再多谈一些关于这个的内容。
how to make this durable.
如何使其耐用。
And next time,
下次，
thank you.
谢谢你。
And this Thursday,
而这个星期四，
it's Veterans Day.
今天是退伍军人节。
I hope that you are going to enjoy a well deserved lighter day.
希望你能享受一个应得的轻松日子。
You can get some rest.
你可以休息一下。
I'll see you next week.
下周见。
Bye.
再见。